Jean Dupuis, Agile coach, PMP

Agile coach and Agile Product Owner at OPEN

Summary

With over 20 years experience in leading major IT and organizational projects and developping consulting services in information systems, I've become a professionnal in helping organisations to leverage energies to make successfull changes in organization, processes, and IT.

I've been in the recent past managing portfolios of projects in software industry for major customers in Elcrtonics (Schneider), Telecoms (Orange), transports (SNCF). I'm also an Affiliate Professor at Grenoble Management School in Agility, Consulting services, portfolio management, project management and IS urbanisation.

Since 2008 when I discovered the agile manifesto and agility... I decided to go as fast as possible in Agile. I've been managing and helping other managers to turn their operations in agile mode, to embrace agile culture, spirit and practices, to go always further in agility, searching for excellence. The teams I coach witness how this professional switch has been a major transformation in their professional life. I'm proud to have done this and I'm always ready and eager to help those who really want to discover another way to work, with excellence as a target, fun and personnal accomplishment in a very inclusive mode in a strong and happy team.

Specialties: People, organization, effective meetings, coaching, IT projects, Change management, Information systems, PMI, Project Management, PMP, Portfolio management, Leadership, Agile teams, Organisational management, Process management

Experience

Agile coach & Agile Product Owner

December 2010 - Present

For the last few years since I discovered agility in 2008, I've been fully commited to make agility happen in my professional life. I've been very impressed by the importance of the change it represented in my working world; the picture was pleasant, seemed to be an inaccessible dream... But I'm stubborn and I truly believe I (and you) can change the world, where I am, my world. So I've done it, adopting the agile mindset. I knew it would probably not be perfect at first and that I and we would have to inspect & adapt. And it worked so easily I could not believe it! My team grew, people wanted to join the team... a vertuous circle was born. Then, I've been asked to help other managers to turn agile mode with their teams... and it worked the same way.

Now, I'm a transformation agent, acting as an agile coach, helping companies to embrace agility with success. I also train people and I'm still involved in the agile club in Grenoble; we have launched in 2016 the AGILE

LAB, a practice innovation workshop in Agile Grenoble. I've led the MANAGER track with my mate Franck Rageade!! Join us for the 10 years of this major French Agile Event http://agile-grenoble.org.

During these last years I mainly worked for SNCF (french railraod), Schneider Electric, Orange, BioMERIEUX, Banque Populaire des Alpes and also for a fast growing Start-up in the digital world: BEE-BUZZINESS

Portfolio, Programs and Project Director at OPEN

December 2010 - September 2014 (3 years 10 months)

I'm leading technical teams developping software solutions for major industry Key Accounts: ORANGE, SNCF, SCHNEIDER ELECTRIC. We work on several tempos, from classical approaches for project and product development (PMI + cascades) to agile practices (SCRUM). I manage as well big projects as TMAs.

Independant consultant

December 2007 - November 2010 (3 years)

I was offering consulting services operating in France, Grenoble, Lyon and Paris.

I was oriented on improving business management throught various core competencies:

- decision process including all what a manager needs : communication, persuasive skills, negociation skills, a scorecard...
- management: how to manage people, delegation, control, how to manage changes, risks...
- organisation and process management : how to design or adapt organisation and processes to imprve performance, fasten decision making...
- project management : leading projects in a collaborative mode, understanding each party's goals, managing transversal teams, managing delays, quality, budget and scope
- IT management : establishing or updating IT strategic scheme that serves the firm's strategy, PMO, fonctionnal architecture, master data management...

Manager at Ineum Consulting (ex. Deloitte Consulting)

2003 - 2007 (5 years)

Managed consulting projects with a 18 people consultants team, in Information Systems matters.

Manager at Deloitte Management Solutions

2001 - 2003 (3 years)

Consultant at Metris racheté par Vision Consulting Group

1998 - 2001 (4 years)

Conseil spécialisé en gestion de projet dans le domaine privé (en particulier bancaire) et public (administrations, établissements...).

Racheté depuis par Vision Consulting Group.

Consultant at Bossard Consultants

1997 - 1998 (2 years)

Consultant at Gemini Consulting

1997 - 1998 (2 years)

Auditor at Price Waterhouse

1993 - 1994 (2 years)

Auditor at Price Waterhouse

1993 - 1994 (2 years)

Education

University of South Florida - College of Business Administration

MBA, Marketing & Finance, Intl affairs, 2002 - 2002

Activities and Societies: Sailing team

Université Paris Dauphine

Management Master Degree, Marketing & Finance, Intl affairs, 1988 - 1996

Jean Dupuis, Agile coach, PMP

Agile coach and Agile Product Owner at OPEN



Contact Jean on LinkedIn